The truth can be adjusted.
Michael Clayton is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Tony Gilroy.
A law firm brings in its "fixer" to remedy the situation after a lawyer has a breakdown while representing
a chemical company that he knows is guilty in a multi-billion dollar class action suit.
Michael Clayton, played by George Clooney.
Arthur Edens, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Karen Crowder, played by Tilda Swinton.
Barry Grissom, played by Michael O'Keefe.
Marty Bach, played by Sydney Pollack.
Bridget Klein (voice), played by Danielle Skraastad.
Michael Clayton is a 2007 American legal thriller film written and
directed by Tony Gilroy in his directorial debut.
It stars George Clooney as lawyer Michael Clayton, who discovers a
coverup of criminal wrongdoing by one of his firm's clients.
Tom Wilkinson, Tilda Swinton, and Sydney Pollack appear in supporting roles.
Released on October 5, 2007, the film grossed $93 million worldwide.
It was praised for Gilroy's direction and screenplay, and the performances
of the cast, with Swinton's performance particularly lauded.
Michael Clayton was nominated for seven Academy Awards: Best Picture, Best Director, Best Original Score, Best Original Screenplay,
Best Actor for Clooney, Best Supporting Actor for Wilkinson, and Best Supporting Actress for Swinton, which she won.
The film explores themes of new york city, killing, chambers
of a barrister, restaurant, fake suicide.
The tone is emotional and intense.